Okay.
Now we're going to review the source code for the IWC publish subscribed implementation and we're going
to expand it to publish the temperature and humidity sensor data as well as the received signal strength
of the Wi-Fi connection so that we can view this data from the MQ RTT test client.
All right.
So starting from main that see here we're calling a WAC Iot start so go ahead and control left click
to follow that function.
And here I've added the test candle for the WC Iot task and to check for null to ensure that it's created
only once in the event that the callback function is invoked multiple times.
And here the test candle is created and initialized to null.
Okay, let's continue.
And here we have our certificates, which doesn't need much explanation as we dealt with this in the
previous lesson where we saw that the embedded certificates are required by a WSU T and these are actually
included as part of the NQT initialization in the AWB Iot task, which we'll see shortly.
And then we have the nQt host URL, which we've updated via the SDK config.
But this could also be defined directly in the source code, if you prefer.
And then next we have the amputee port, which is port eight eight, eight three.
And then there are the subscribe and disconnect callback handlers.
And we saw how the subscribe callback logs, the topic data and the disconnect handler either attempts
to reconnect automatically or manually.
And I'll show you where the auto reconnect functionality is enabled when we get further down the file.
Then we have the WC Iot task and first an array for the payload is created and there's also the variable
AI, which is used as a message counter.
But I won't use this variable as we make adjustments, but you can feel free to keep it if you like.
And then here we have some instances that originate from the MWC Iot Device SDK, and that's for the
AWB Society client, NQT initialization parameters, connection parameters and parameters for both quality
of service level zero and quality of service level one messages and then the lines that follow.
Take care of the NQT in it parameters such as auto reconnect.
Host You are will the port are embedded certificates NQT command time out in milliseconds, the TLS
handshake timeout, the SSL hostname verify and then the disconnect callback handler is provided.
And then the disconnect handler data is null and once the NQT parameters are initialized then the WC
Iot nQt init function is called and a reference to the AWB Iot client is passed to the function along
with the NQT in IT parameters.
Then the connection parameters are initialized for the Iot client connection along with our config AWB
example client ID, which is defined in the AWB Iot header file.
And this is also your things name in a society.
And just as a reminder, this is the client I did that I had given in the head of file.
Okay, now let's go back to where we were.
So after the connection parameters are initialized here, we then attempt the connection to a wc using
a wc iet nqt connect and we do this at a 1/2 interval while the RC variable is not equal to success.
And then here is where the auto reconnect functionality is enabled and that's done using a WSU T and
duty auto reconnect set status.
And this is the same auto reconnect functionality that I had mentioned for the disconnect callback handler.
Then the topic name is defined and its length is obtained so that we could use it in the wc iet mq to
subscribe function.
And this function also takes the Iot subscribe callback handler function name as a parameter.
So this is how we subscribe.
Okay.
Next, the quality of service zero and quality of service one parameters are initialized and the payload
variable is required.
Here it is casted as a void pointer.
And the payload variable is what we pass our data into in publishing.
Next we drop into the wild loop and we stay there as long as we have one of the mentioned status is
returned and then the a wc iet kuti yield function.
We'll wait for the red messages and then they get stack high watermark.
Free Auto API is used to get the remaining stack in bytes and another API is used to return the name
of the task and it's log to the console and then we have a delay which controls how often we want to
publish data.
So I'll go ahead and increase that to 3000 milliseconds.
And then here we use as printf to update the payload for quality of service zero.
So now let's go ahead and updated to include the received signal strength of the Wi-Fi connection and
I'll include the function here, which will define shortly.
But for now, let's just update the text and we'll update the text to, say, wi fi or a.
And then here we'll include the function wi fi app, get RSS side.
And this function will return an end.
So the rest of the sprint def statement is fine and the next we'll need to update the payload length
and then call a WC iota in Q2 to publish to publish data for quality of service zero.
And this takes care of publishing data for quality of service zero messages.
Next, let's update the payload for quality of service level one messages, which will include a temperature
and humidity sensor data.
So now let's just add the text for temperature.
Then let's add the get temperature function.
Then let's also update the sprint def type for the return of get temperature to a float type with one
decimal point.
Then let's add another string for humidity and let's also include the type for the get humidity function
return.
Okay.
Now we'll just need to add the text for humidity.
And then let's add the function as well.
Okay.
Then the next step includes updating the payload length once again, but this time for quality of service
one and then calling a wc iut in Q2 to publish to publish the data.
Then, since it's quality of service one, we check for the acknowledgement.
Okay, that looks good.
So now let's add the HD 22 dot H for our temperature and humidity functions.
All right.
Now we can go to wi fi updates and create the prototype for the get RSA function.
Okay.
And this function gets the RSS value.
Of the Wi-Fi connection.
In the return.
Is the current RSI level.
And the return is a type.
And it's called wi fi app.
Get on a suicide.
And that's void.
Okay.
Now let's go to the C file and define it.
So let's first copy the name and the return type.
Now.
Let's go all the way down to the bottom.
And paste it down here.
And now we need an instance of the wi fi app record type.
And call it wi fi data.
And then let's ESP check.
ESP wifi stay get app info.
And then we're going to pass the Wi-Fi app record type.
Okay.
And that is a reference to Wi-Fi data.
And then we simply return the Wi-Fi data.
An access to RSI structure.
A member.
All right.
And here is where we could find the wi fi app record.
Along with the RSI member.
Okay.
Now let's build this and test it out.
In a flash it.
All right, now let's bring up the console.
Okay.
And this all looks good.
Yep.
That looks all right.
So now let's go to the WC and cu t test client and confirm that the values are logged.
Okay, perfect.
Our published data now includes the temperature, humidity and RSA side, and that's really great.
So now we can check the strength of the Wi-Fi connection as well as the temperature, humidity or whatever
other data you want to publish from anywhere in the world.
And that is really awesome.
And now that you had the foundation of the wireless local area network and now you know how to integrate
a cloud framework like a WC, you can now confidently explore other cloud frameworks if a WC isn't the
one for you.
All right, so I really hope you enjoyed this, and I hope to see you again soon.